Guide to the Voegtly Evangelical Church, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1833-1981 AIS.1985.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Voegtly Evangelical Church, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records
1833-1981
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Voegtly Evangelical Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1985.11
3 microfilm_reels (1960 frames)
The records of Voegtly Evangelical Church contain church history, registers, bulletins, and cemetery records, 1833-1981.
History
The Voegtly Evangelical Church is a German-language Protestant Church Established in 1833 by Swiss immigrants to Allegheny City (presently North Side, Pittsburgh, Pa.). Named for Nicholas Voegtly, Sr. who donated the land as a site for the first (one story) brick church in 1833. Known in former times as the German United Evangelical Protestant Church, Allegheny, Pa., and later as Pilgram Evangelical Church.
Scope and Content Notes
The Records of Voegtly Evangelical Church contain church history; 100th anniversary booklet; church bulletins; church registers, including deaths, marriages, baptisms, and confirmations; and Cemetary records including inserts; Reel 3 includes additional cemetery grave records that were filmed by the Western Pennsylvania Genealogical Society in 1986. They have been assigned 85:11, Reel 3, designation to keep them in close proximity to the records microfilmed earlier. These records give names, age, grave location (block. lot); in addition one may find lists of children's graves, and notes on internments.
NOTE: Records up unitl 1910 are in German and some registers contain lists of names.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were a gift from Voegtly Evangelical Church, Pittsburgh, Pa., 1985.
Existence and Location of Copies
This collection has been microfilmed by Archives Service Center and the Western Pennsylvania Genealogical Society from originals in the possession of the Detre Library and Archives at the Heinz History Center, 1985.
Previous Citation
Voegtly Evangelical Church, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, AIS.1985.11, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Voegtly Evangelical Church (North Side, Pittsburgh, Pa.), Records, 1833-1981.
Swiss -- Pennsylvania; Church records and registers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Swiss -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Histories; Germans -- Pennsylvania; Germans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Dutchtown (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Swiss Bottom (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Allegheny (Pa.); Newsletters; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Religion; Pennsylvania -- Church history; North Side (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Baptismal records; Indexes; Ethnic groups; German Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Religion; Churches and Synagogues; Swiss Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Religion; Cemeteries -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Evangelical Church -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; German United Evangelical Protestant Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Pilgrim Evangelical Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.); United Evangelical Church -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Voegtly Evangelical Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Evangelical Association of North America
- Historical Materials, I.
  - Typescript History, 1958 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
  - 100th Anniversary (1833-1933) (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
  - Church Bulletins, 1980-1981 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
- Church Registers, II.
  - Volume 1, 1.
    - Deaths, 1833-1966 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
    - Marriages, 1833-1857 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
  - Volume 2, 2.
    - Baptisms, 1833-1841 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
    - Confirmations, 1833-1953 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
  - Volume 3, 3.
    - Confirmations, 1868-1956 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
  - Volume 4-6, 4.
    - Baptisms, 1841-1966 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
  - Volume 7-8, 5.
    - Marriages, 1857-1957 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 2)
  - Volume 9-10, 6.
    - Deaths, 1848-1873 1898-1956 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 2)
- Cemetery Records, III.
  - Volume 11, 1881-1927 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 2)
  - Volume 12, 1907-1964 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 2)
  - Volume 13, 1872-1911 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 2)
  - Volume 14, 1925-1968 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 2)
  - Volume 15, 1966-1967 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 2)
- Cemetery Grave Record, IV.
  - Volume 1, 1871-1919 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 2, Reel 3)